Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Colin Dawkins Papers, 1776-1986 RL.00679
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Colin Dawkins papers
1776-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00679
7.9 Linear Feet
circa 3,800 Items
Access Restrictions
Access to portions of The Colin Dawkins Papers is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Colin Dawkins Papers were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987. Processing of this collection was supported in part by gifts from the J. Walter Thompson Company Fund and the John and Kelly Hartman Foundation.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1922, Sept. 8 Born on an Indian reservation near Tulsa, Oklahoma
1930s Grew up in New York City, where he studied art and planned to be a portrait painter
1943, March - Sept. Worked with WABC radio's wartime all-night record operation
1943, Sept. 10 - 1946, Mar. 8 In the Air Corps; advanced from private to corporal; worked in public relations and on corps newspapers
1947 Began his 34 year career at the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) as a mailroom messenger in the New York office. He shortly thereafter advanced to be a market research clerk.
1949, Jan. Appointed Junior Copywriter, assistant to Larry D'Aloise at JWT
1949, Sept. - 1951, Feb. Assigned to JWT-London's copy group; first American to join the London office after the WWII hiatus; worked on Pan American and Parker Pen accounts
1950, Dec. Started JWT/BMRB (British Market Research Bureau) News, renamed Round the Square, the London office's house publication
ca. 1950 Married Patricia Horan, an American who worked in the London office's Art Department
1951 Returned to New York Office
1952, April - 1953, Mar. Worked in Montreal office on Barrett and Dominion Glass accounts
1953 Rejoined New York office, writing on a variety of accounts including Ford international, Mosler Safe Co., Blue Cross, and J B. Williams
1953-1971 Worked on Ford account
1962-ca. 1978 Principal assignments consisted of Ford-Ford Division Magazine, Outdoor, Advance Projects and International
1965 Named a Vice President
1972, Oct. Sent to Paris office as Creative Director
1978 Proposed writing a history of JWT which he worked on for several years as a part-time JWT employee
1981 Retired from J. Walter Thompson Company
1986 November 27 Died in Pennsylvania
Collection Overview
The papers of Colin Dawkins, a former Vice President of the J. Walter Thompson (JWT) advertising agency, span the years 1776 to 1986 with the bulk of the papers being dated between 1920 and 1981. The collection consists of Dawkins's research files, gathered for a proposed book on the history of the advertising business as it paralleled and was influenced by the growth and international development of JWT. These files contain correspondence, printed materials (including JWT newsletters), articles, clippings, speeches, writings, advertisements, reports, oral interview transcripts and cassette tapes. Clients represented in this collection include primarily the Ford Motor Company but also Kraft, Chesebrough-Ponds, Pan American, and Lever Brothers, and JWT executives represented include James Walter Thompson, Stanley Resor, Howard Kohl, Sam Meek, Helen Lansdowne Resor, Edward G. Wilson, Shirley Woodell, James Webb Young, and Dan Seymour. Much of the collection duplicates material found elsewhere in the extensive J. Walter Thompson Company Archives and many items are photocopies; however, the collection does contain unique material specifically in the Oral Interview Series and items thoughout the collection which Colin Dawkins collected.
In October 1978, Dawkins began his advertising history project. During the next two years, he wrote to “JWT vets” requesting information about people and places, letters and memos, excerpts from speeches, artifacts, advertisements, pictures, and information on JWT offices.
The Officers and Staff Series contains information by and about key personalities who contributed to the development of the J. Walter Thompson Company. The JWT employees represent the majority of the company's departments: broadcast, research, creative, international, publicity and public relations, and the executive administration. Especially well-documented individuals include Gelston Hardy, Kennett Hinks, Howard Kohl, Sam Meek, John Monsarrat, Helen Lansdowne Resor, Stanley Resor, Dan Seymour, Norman H. Strouse, James Walter Thompson, Edward G. Wilson, Shirley Woodell, and James Webb Young.
The Clients Series consists of background information on a limited number of major and minor JWT clients, including Kraft, Pan American, Chesebrough-Ponds, Lever Brothers, and Ford Motor Company. Dawkins worked for many years on the Ford account, for which there is extensive information in this series. The Ford files document the 1957 “Around the World” campaign, international campaigns, background information on campaigns for Mustang and Maverick models, the history of JWT's relationship with Ford, presentations made to Ford, and Ford firsts in advertising.
The Alphabetical Files Series is the largest series in the collection. The majority of information focuses on JWT through short company histories, the establishment and growth of departments (such as Broadcast and Radio), and both domestic and international offices, especially New York and London. The Alphabetical Files Series also documents JWT's innovations in the advertising business in the use of market research, testimonials, and women's perspective in advertising. The series contains some information about other advertising agencies in particular Batten, Barton, Durstine, Osborn; Lord & Thomas; Foote, Cone & Belding; and N. W. Ayer. Other topics in this series include general advertising history and economic comparisons of advertising agencies. Dawkins's research notes and correspondence files he kept for his advertising history project are in this series also.
Dawkins travelled to visit key officers and staff members and recorded and transcribed their conversations. The cassettes and transcripts from these interviews are in the Oral Interview Series in both the Audio Subseries and the Transcripts Subseries. They provide personal insights into the history of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
After three years of researching, Dawkins set out to write a history of advertising focussing on the J. Walter Thompson Company. The resulting text, entitled “Ain't It Hell On A Windy Day” was not published. The manuscript copy is in the Writings Series and is CLOSED except to the members of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
The Advertisements Series is filed with the Oversize Material and contains the advertisements associated with specific Officers and Staff, Clients, and files in the Alphabetical Files. Also in this series are advertisements from Dawkins's Advertisement Portfolio.
Advertising -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies -- New York; Ford Motor Company; Dawkins, Colin, 1922-1986; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company; Resor, Helen Lansdowne, 1886-1964; Meek, Samuel W. (Samuel Williams), 1895-; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Resor, Stanley Burnet, 1879-1962; Seymour, Dan, 1914-
- Officers and Staff Series, 1873-1986 (bulk 1920s-1979)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, biographical information, clippings, notes, photographs, and articles about or by JWT staff members. Employees represented are primarily from the U. S. offices; however, William Hinks, Douglas Saunders, and Rae Smith are from the London office, and the James Hamilton Russell and Timothy Hamilton Russell files contain information about the South Africa office.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by last name of employee. See also Oversize Materials.
  - Adams, Taylor, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Carlton, William J., 1873-1874, 1902, 1961-1965 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Carroll, 1952, 1957, 1964-1967, 1971-1972, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Cherington, Paul, 1922-1929, 1931, 1939, and undated (Box 1)
  - Connell, Louise Fox, 1923, 1979 (Box 1)
  - D'Aloise, Larry, 1960, 1962-1963, 1966-1967 and undated (Box 1)
  - Day, William, 1928, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Dennison, Robert E., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Elton, Wallace, 1949, 1958-1959, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Fielden, E.J., 1959 and undated (Box 1)
  - Flower, Henry, 1930, 1947, 1954, 1979 and undated (Box 1)
  - Francisco, Don, 1945-1949, 1952, 1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Graham, William J., undated (Box 1)
  - Hamilton Russell, James, 1920s-1956 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton Russell, Timothy, 1970, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Hardy, Gelston, 1907, 1930, 1944-1945, 1948, 1953, 1956, 1958, 1966, 1979-1983, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Henderson, Howard, 1920, 1928-1938 and undated (Box 1)
  - Hinks, Kennett, 1925, 1930, 1947, 1949, 1963-1966, 1978-1979, 1982, 1985 and undated (Box 1)
  - Hinks, William, 1940, 1960, 1967 and undated (Box 1)
  - Hobbs, Arthur E., 1931, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Jaccaci, Thayer, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Jessup, John K., undated (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Arno H., 1947, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Johnston, Don, See Oversize Material (Box 1)
  - King, Peggy, 1928, 1963, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Kinney, Gilbert, 1924, 1930, 1938, 1952, 1985 and undated (Box 2)
  - Kohl, Howard, 1906, 1926, 1948, 1956-1957, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Lanigan, Denis, speeches, 1984, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Marquand, John, 1972 (Box 2)
  - McKee, Rudyard C., 1959, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Meek, Sam, 1917, 1919, 1924-1925, 1929-1973, 1977-1982, 1984 and undated, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Merrick, Robert, 1929, 1980 and undated (Box 2)
  - Monsarrat, John, 1955, 1960-1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Odell, John A., undated (Box 2)
  - Olson, Sidney, 1961, 1974, 1979 and undated (Box 2)
  - O'Meara, Walter, 1930-1952 (Box 2)
  - Raymond, Charles E., 1890s, 1920-1930, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Reber, John, 1930-1931, 1947, 1958, 1971, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 3)
  - Reed, Vergil D., 1949, 1979 and undated (Box 3)
  - Reese, Florence, 1959, 1979-1980 and undated (Box 3)
  - Resor, Helen, 1920, 1924, 1936, 1963-1964 and undated (Box 3)
  - Resor, Helen and Stanley, 1917, 1927-1928, 1937-1938, 1947, 1955, 1963, 1968, 1983 and undated (Box 3)
  - Resor, Helen; her sister Therese Lansdowne Duble, 1968, 1981 and undated (Box 3)
  - Resor, Stanley, 1901-1983 and undated, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Richardson, George, 1948, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Richey, Hunter, 1949, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Saunders, Douglas, 1946, 1949, 1957, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Schachte, Henry, 1963-1964, 1969, 1972, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Senior, Raimond del Noce, 1965-1966, 1973, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Seymour, Dan, 1958-1979 (Box 3)
  - Seymour, Dan, speeches, 1966-1972 (Box 4)
  - Smith, Rae, 1924, 1930, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Stansbury, Harold, 1921, 1924, 1954, 1955 and undated (Box 4)
  - Stanton, Henry T., 1924, 1927, 1940s, 1954 and undated (Box 4)
  - Steichen, Edward, 1927-1928, 1963 and undated (Box 4)
  - Strouse, Norman, 1956, 1964-1976, 1979, 1984 and undated (Box 4)
  - Taylor, Winfield, 1949, 1957, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Thompson, James Walter, 1893-1907, 1921, 1926, 1928, 1930, 1935-1937, 1950, 1958, 1962, 1964, 1968, 1976, 1979 and undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Watson, John B., 1921-1929, 1958, 1979 and undated (Box 5)
  - Wilson, Edward B., 1964, 1973, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Wilson, Edward G., 1930-1986 and undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Woodell, Shirley, 1947-1980, 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Young, James Webb, 1916-1965 (Box 5)
  - Young, James Webb, 1922-1982 and undated, 5 folders (Box 6)
- Clients Series, 1895-1979 (bulk 1957-1960s)
  Contains printed materials, correspondence, articles, clippings, press releases, and account histories of JWT clients that Dawkins researched for his book.
  Arranged alphabetically by client's name. See also Oversize Materials.
  - Clients Lists, 1920-1978 and undated (Box 6)
  - American Memorial Chapel Committee, (London Office), 1959 and undated (Box 6)
  - Cheek-Neal Coffee Company, (Maxwell House), 1925-1927 (Box 6)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1916, 1940, 1950, 1959, 1963 and undated (Box 6)
  - Fleischmann Company, 1925-1926 and undated (Box 6)
  - Ford Motor Company, 38 folders
    - General, 1908, 1928, 1943-1960, 1978 and undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Argentina: Falcon, Futura and Taunus, 1963, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Around the World Campaign 1948, 1957, 1 folder (Box 6)
    - Around the World Campaign 1957, 1979, 7 folders (Box 7)
    - Campaign Themes, 1957-1979 (Box 7)
    - Code Name Fox: The Story of Ford Fairmont and Mercury Zephyr, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Fairlane, 1966 Nov. 15 (Box 8)
    - Cortina, 1969 and undated (Box 8)
    - Ford and JWT: a dialogue prepared as an orientation for Bunky Knudson, 1968, Aug. 8 (Box 8)
    - The Ford Book of Styling, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Ford dealers' Closed Circuit Television Conference, 1954, Jan. 28 (Box 8)
    - The Ford Image in Europe, 1976, Sept. 15 (Box 8)
    - Ford International: Considerations for Strengthening Ford's Position in the Expanding European Market, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Ford International: Product Value Campaign, 1963, Dec. 5 (Box 8)
    - Germany, 1966 and undated (Box 8)
    - History, 1961, 1963, 1969, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Iacocca's Questions, 1970, Jan. 10 (Box 8)
    - Magazine and Newspaper Follow-ups for 1965, 1964, Aug. 4 (Box 8)
    - Maverick, 1964, 1968, 1969 and undated (Box 8)
    - Mustang, 1963-1966, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Newark Ford Dealer Advertising Association fires JWT, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Organizational Chart, undated (Box 9)
    - Printed Materials, 1964, 1966, 1970, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Product Value Campaign, 1962 (Box 9)
    - A Quick Look at Maverick on Brazil, 1977, Sept. 26 (Box 10)
    - The Reality Project, 1968, June (Box 10)
    - Understanding Pop Culture in the Marketplace, presentation by Ford Creative Group for Don Frey, 1966 and undated (Box 10)
  - Franklin Baker Co., Baker's Coconut, 1924 (Box 10)
  - General Cigar Company, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Grand Rapids Refrigerator Co., 1916 and undated (Box 10)
  - Henry McKenna bourbon, 1967, June 13 (Box 10)
  - Irving Trust Company, 1925 (Box 10)
  - Kraft, 1904, 1959, 1964, 1972, 1977 and undated (Box 10)
  - Lever Brothers: Lux and Rinso, 1925, 1935, 1950, 1966 and undated (Box 10)
  - Pabst Malt, 1895 (Box 10)
  - Pan American World Airways, (campaigns 1943-1969), 1956,1959 and undated (Box 10)
  - Prudential Insurance Company, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Shell Oil Company, 1930, 1938, 1942, 1952-1953, 1960 and undated (Box 10)
- Alphabetical Files Series, 1776, 1912-1985 (bulk 1950s-1970s)
  Consists of articles, clippings, printed materials, chronologies, notes and excerpts from publications, correspondence, writings, and speeches. In this series exists a unique history of JWT's offices in Spain.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title. See also Oversize Materials.
  - Advertisements (primarily photocopies), 1912-1948, 1950 and undated (Box 10)
  - Advertising & Marketing History Articles by Richard W. Pollay, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - Advertising Hall of Fame, 1973-1979 (Box 10)
  - Advertising History from Babylonian times through the 1980s, 1857, 1959-1980 (Box 10)
  - Agency Rankings, 1916-1980 (Box 10)
  - American Business History, excerpts from, undated (Box 10)
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine, Osborn, History of Company, 1954, 1961-1962, 1966 (Box 10)
  - British Admen Know People Better than Politicians, by Jeremy Bullmore, 1977, May 25 (Box 10)
  - British Market Research Bureau, London, 1960, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Broadcast Advertising--Radio, 1895-1978 and undated (Box 11)
  - Broadcast Advertising--Television, 1937-1979 (Box 11)
  - “Close-up: London” (speech, author unidentified), 1985 (Box 11)
  - Competitive Advertising Agencies, 1955-1979 (Box 11)
  - Dawkins' Chonological Research Notes, 1864-1980 (Box 11)
  - Dawkins' Project Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Dawkins' Project Notes, ca. 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Expenditure Data, 1956-1960 (Box 11)
  - Freedom of Choice Campaign of the Magazine Publishers Association, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
  - Historical Exhibit on the 11th Floor, New York office, 1977 and undated (Box 11)
  - The History of Advertising Archives (Vancouver, Canada), 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - The History of Advertising Trust (London), 1977-1979 (Box 11)
  - History of the J. Walter Thompson Company, 1864-1962 by Frankie McKee Robins, 1962, Jan. (Box 11)
  - Internal and External Communications Recommended Plan, 1976 (Box 11)
  - The J. Walter Thompson Company: An Advertising History, 1979 (Box 11)
  - JWT Handbook, 1976, Oct. 26 (Box 11)
  - JWT Historical Project (Archives), 1977 (Box 11)
  - JWT History Presentation, 1980, April 22 (Box 11)
  - JWT: Article written for the Book of Knowledge Encyclopedia, 1978, Sept. 27 (Box 11)
  - JWT: Articles about the Company, 1916-1972 (Box 11)
  - JWT: Broadcast Advertising, 1926-1962 (Box 11)
  - JWT: Copy Analysis--Bourbon Print Advertising, 1967 (Box 12)
  - JWT: Copy and Plan Department Policy, 1915, 1930 and undated (Box 12)
  - JWT: Creativity, 1917, 1957, 1960, 1964-1965, 1971 and undated (Box 12)
  - JWT: Handbook for Personnel, 1947-1961, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - JWT: House Ads, 1889, 1917, 1953-1960, 1970 and undated (Box 12)
  - JWT: Howard Henderson Documents, 1904-1962 (Box 12)
  - JWT: Howard Henderson Documents v. 2, 1939-1980 (Box 12)
  - JWT: International Advertising Agency, 1937 (Box 12)
  - JWT: International Expansion, 1927-1980 (Box 12)
  - JWT: Jokes from other countries, 1966 (Box 12)
  - JWT: Management Transition clippings, 1974-1979 and undated (Box 13)
  - JWT: Memorabilia, pictures of, undated (Box 13)
  - JWT: Motion Picture Department, 1930, 1947 (Box 13)
  - JWT: New Business Presentations, 1952, 1958, 1971 (Box 13)
  - JWT: New Business speech, An Opportunity for J. Walter Thompson To Become Identified as the Leading Factor in Today's 'New Product' Economy, author unknown, 1957, July 17 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Newsletters (originals and copies), 1928, 1963-1966 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Personnel Data, 1931, 1952, 1975-1977 and undated (Box 13)
  - JWT: Personnel Lists and addresses, 1924-1980 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Radio Department, 1928-1978 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Resor Library, What is the, 1927, Dec. 26 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Research and Planning Department, 1923, 1932, 1953-1954, 1956-1960, 1969, 1978-1980 and undated (Box 13)
  - JWT: Retirement Trust and Stockholders Information, 1972-1979 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Company: A Starting Point for Future Growth, 1959 (Box 13)
  - JWT: Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Company: A Starting Point for Future Growth, 1959, 1972 revisions (Box 13)
  - JWT: Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Company: A Starting Point for Future Growth, condensed for Howard Henderson's opening talk to the “Eyes on Thompson” group, 1960 (Box 13)
  - JWT Staff Quotes, undated (Box 13)
  - JWT: TV and Radio Department, 1930-1964 and undated (Box 14)
  - JWT: Testimonial Advertising, 1930, 1935 (Box 14)
  - JWT: Wartime Advertising, undated (Box 14)
  - JWT: Women In Advertising, clippings, 1928-1931, 1938, 1948, 1951, 1963, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Lord & Thomas-Albert Lasker-Foote, Cone & Belding, 1929, 1959-1962, 1968-1972 and undated (Box 14)
  - Magazines, History of, 1925-1930 and undated (Box 14)
  - Marschner, Don, Birth of a Giant (The economic aspects of the early history of advertising agencies.), 1962 (Box 14)
  - Munro, Dave, clippings about libel suits against Munro, then editor of Space & Time, 1940-1946, 1961 (Box 14)
  - N.W. Ayer, History of Company, 1967, 1969, 1973 and undated (Box 14)
  - Newspapers, History of, 1935, 1978 and undated (Box 14)
  - Offices: Australia, 1930, 1931, 1937, 1957, 1962, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Caracas, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Canada, 1932, 1958, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Chicago, 1926-1927, 1935, 1946, 1948, 1959, 1962-1969, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Cincinnati, 1930 and undated (Box 14)
  - Offices: Detroit, 1916, 1965 and undated (Box 14)
  - Offices: Domestic and International Lists, 1927-1937 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Frankfurt, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Offices: Hollywood, 1938, 1956-1957, 1961, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Offices: India, 1949-1950, 1962 (Box 14)
  - Offices: London, 1919, 1921, 1925, 1928, 1930-1931, 1948-1951, 1953-1954, 1959-1962, 1964-1965, 1969, 1971, 1976, 1978-1979, 1985, 1986 and undated, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Offices: Los Angeles, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Mexico, 1952 (Box 15)
  - Offices: New York, 1917-1929, 1932, 1937, 1946, 1953, 1957-1958, 1961-1965, 1975, 1979-1980 and undated (Box 15)
  - Offices: Paris, 1959, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Peru, 1957-1958 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Philippines, 1960, 1974-1977 and undated (includes Ford campaign research and advertisements) (Box 15)
  - Offices: Regions: Asia/Pacific, 1956 and Latin America, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Offices: St. Louis, 1930 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Sao Paulo, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Offices: South Africa, 1933, 1977, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Spain: J. Walter Thompson España from 1927 to 1936, by Julian Bravo, ca. 1976 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Toyko, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Offices: Washington, D. C., 1960, 1963, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Peoria Journal Star Project, (re: newspaper design and function), 1969 (Box 15)
  - Picture Sources for Dawkins's Book, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 15)
  - The Philosophy of Advertising (typescript preface to a book), by Garritt Lydecker, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Quotations and Anecdotes about the Advertising Industry, ca. 1924-1985 (Box 15)
  - Research in Advertising Awards, 1925-1931 and undated (Box 15)
  - Townsend & Townsend, advertising evaluations company, 1938, 1947, 1978 and undated (Box 15)
  - Unilever Conference on Creative Advertising Principles; Some Things We Have Learned, a speech, presented by Dan Seymour, 1962, Nov. 29 (Box 15)
- Oral Interviews Series, 1979-1980
  Consists of two subseries: Transcripts and Audio.
  - Transcripts Subseries, 1977, 1979-1980
    Consists of interviews conducted by Dawkins either in person or over the telephone. Don Johnston's interview was conducted by others in Bombay, India and there are two interviews with Louise Fox Connell, one by Dawkins and another by Rosamond Hartshorn in 1977. Some files contain multiple transcripts that are annotated by the interviewee.
    Arranged alphabetically by interviewee's name.
    - Adams, Taylor, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Connell, Louise Fox, 1977, 1979 (Box 16)
    - D'Aloise, Larry, 1979, June 20 (Box 16)
    - Devine, Jack, 1979, Aug. 14 (Box 16)
    - Elton, Wallace, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Flower, Henry, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Hamilton Russell, Timothy, 1979, Oct. 30 (Box 16)
    - Hardy, Gelston, 1979, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Henderson, Howard, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Hinks, Kennett, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Hobbs, Arthur E., 1979 (Box 17)
    - Johnston, Don, 1980, Dec. 3 (Box 17)
    - King, Peggy, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Kohl, Howard, 1979, June 21 and Nov. 8 (Box 17)
    - Lanigan, Denis, 1979, Oct. 19 (Box 17)
    - Lord, Walter, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Meek, Sam, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Moloney, Ted, see Mygatt, Phil and Ted Moloney, 1979, Nov. 13 (Box 17)
    - Monsarrat, John, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Mygatt, Phil and Ted Moloney, 1979, Nov. 13 (Box 17)
    - Olson, Sidney, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Reese, Florence, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Strouse, Norman, 1979, Oct. 23 (Box 18)
    - Tempest, Margaret, 1979 (Box 18)
    - Thompson, Mrs. (Adele) Walter Roosevelt, 1979, Mar. 19 (Box 18)
    - Wilson, Edward G., 1979 (Box 18)